A Guide to the Gordon and Webster Family Papers
University of Virginia Library
- Series III: Ann Gordon Webster (Box-folder 15:13-23:11)
  - 1962 Ann Gordon journal, 1 item (Box-folder 23:4)
    There are loose pages from a notebook about travels by Ann or Harry Webster.
  - 19661984 Ann Gordon journals, 2 items (Box-folder 23:5)
    Ann's notebooks about feedings for children and family tasks.
  - n. d. news clippings, 2 items (Box-folder 23:6)
  - 1935-1947 Ann Gordon report cards, 10 items (Box-folder 23:7)
    Ann's report cards from Camp Alleghany; The Stonefield School (1935-1938;) Saint Anne's School (1940-19450 and Wellesley College (1946-1947)
  - 1945-1949 Ann Gordon school assignments, 25 items (Box-folder 23:8)
    There are mostly essays and stories by Ann Gordon from Saint Anne's and Wellesley including several drafts of "Literature as a Social Criticism".
  - 1946-1954 Ann Gordon University of Virginia, 10 items (Box-folder 23:9)
    There are letters to Ann Gordon from Miss Roy Land, John Cook Wyllie, and Harry Clemons.
  - 1947-1950 Ann Gordon school -related material Wellesley, 21 items (Box-folder 23:10)
    There are correspondence, permissions, and invitations related to Wellesley College.
  - 1966 Ann Gordon Webster: Work: Teacher, 68 items (Box-folder 23:11)
    Class reading materials and questions that Ann Gordon wrote for the classes she was teaching.
- Series IV: Webster Family: Richard Henry and Ann Gordon Webster
  - 1941-1949 Correspondence R. H. Webster to his parents William and Eleanore Webster, 55 items (Box-folder 24:1)
    The Webster family had Winnie-the-Pooh nicknames: William was "K" for Kanga, Eleanore was "Roo," and Harry was "Tig" or "Tigger." Harry wrote to his parents from Camp O-AT-KA about his activities (tennis, baseball, initiation, scotch bridge and rifle try outs). He wrote that they left the ball field to hear President Roosevelt's talk over the" tel-a-tak." He mentioned his friends, Bob Allyn and Abbot Fletcher (For letters about Harry's days in the service in WWII, see Series II William Webster Box 12, in Harry's correspondence with his grandparents)
  - 1946 Correspondence of R. H. Webster and Ann Gordon, 5 items (Box-folder 24:2)
    Included is the letter from Harry Webster inviting Ann to the Harvard-Yale football game and her response.
  - 1947 January-May Correspondence Harry Webster and Ann Gordon, 30 items (Box-folder 24:3)
  - 1947 June-September Correspondence Harry Webster and Ann Gordon, 32 items (Box-folder 24:4)
    Included is a letter from Armistead Gordon, and letters from Harry's parents.
  - 1947 October-December Correspondence R. H. Webster and Ann Gordon, 27 items (Box-folder 24:5)
  - 1948 January-March Correspondence R. H. Webster and Ann Gordon, 44 items (Box-folder 24:6)
  - 1948 April-May Correspondence R. H. Webster and Ann Gordon, 19 items (Box-folder 24:7)
  - 1948 June-December Correspondence R. H. Webster and Ann Gordon, 47 items (Box-folder 24:8)
    Harry mentioned that his father's job became official and William Webster would begin working full time the next week as [James Vincent] Forrestal's deputy for atomic affairs in the Pentagon. Harry graduated from Princeton and travelled to Mexico and Cuba.
  - 1949 January Correspondence of Ann Gordon Webster and her husband R. H. Webster, 40 items (Box-folder 25:1)
    Included is correspondence from other family members including Alice Blodgett, (Harry's maternal grandmother) and his parents.
  - 1949 February-April Correspondence R. H. Webster and Ann Gordon, 38 items (Box-folder 25:2)
  - 1949 May-June Correspondence R. H. Webster and Ann Gordon, 25 items (Box-folder 25:3)
  - 1949 July-December Correspondence R. H. Webster and Ann Gordon, 41 items (Box-folder 25:4)
    Included are news clippings of Harry and Ann's engagement.
  - 1949 Wedding invitation responses, 32 items (Box-folder 25:5)
  - 1949 Wedding invitation responses, 54 items (Box-folder 25:6)
  - 1950 Webster family correspondence, 38 items (Box-folder 26:1)
    Harry discussed with his father the advantages and disadvantages of his father accepting the position of Chairman of the Research and Development in the Department of Defense (being offered by the President of the United States, Harry S. Truman.) Also enclosed are copies of news clippings about Webster's appointment.
  - 1951 Webster family correspondence, 20 items (Box-folder 26:2)
    Bob Ellsworth was visiting William Webster. Harry wrote about their college friends and his son, William Webster "Barney and the "Grub."
  - 1952 Webster family correspondence, 24 items (Box-folder 26:3)
    Harry, Ann, and son Barney (William Webster III) were living in Madrid, Spain. Ann travelled to Frankfurt, Germany for her friend, Sallie Merritt's wedding. Included is correspondence with Alice Blodgett and Vollie Sanderson.
  - 1953 Webster family correspondence, 8 items (Box-folder 26:4)
    Madrid, Spain; There is a letter from Ann to her doctor describing the medical situation in which she had a miscarriage of her second child, Susan Webster. There is also information about her burial.
  - 1954 January-June Webster family correspondence, 34 items (Box-folder 26:5)
    Madrid, Spain
  - 1954 July-December Webster family correspondence, 24 items (Box-folder 26:6)
    Madrid, Spain. Letter from William Webster on August 12 in which he mentioned the Oak Ridge, Tennessee Strike.
  - 1955 Webster family correspondence, 57 items (Box-folder 26:7)
    Alexandria, Va. William Webster mentioned his various trips including San Juan, Puerto Rico; sparring with Denny Roberts; and testifying before joint committee. Irwin Conham was in negotiation with the convicts; Snowden Skinner died of lung cancer. Birth of daughter Liza.
  - 1956 Webster family correspondence, 16 items (Box-folder 26:8)
    William and Eleanore Webster were in Jamaica. Eleanore Webster mentioned Bill's comment that the Compton dinner talk was "high fair but could have been better" but Bill had a cold. Included are letters to and from Stevenson Williams Webster. Harry was staying in London.
  - 1957-1960 Webster family correspondence, 47 items (Box-folder 26:9)
    London, England; Birth of Armistead (Oppit) 1957; birth of Maggie (1959) William Webster wrote about a business trip to Canada with William T. Golden and others. He also mentioned that the opening of Yankee was to be delayed.
  - 1961 January-June Webster family correspondence, 53 items (Box-folder 27:1)
    Harry Webster was in Salisbury, Rhodesia and Ann was taking care of William Webster and the kids after Eleanore was killed in a car accident.
  - 1961 July-December Webster family correspondence, 38 items (Box-folder 27:2)
    Salisbury, Rhodesia. Ann sailed with children to Rhodesia. There are also letters from Steve Webster and Hope Dallam.
  - 1961 Webster family correspondence: letters of sympathy after Eleanore's death, 23 items (Box-folder 27:3)
  - 1962-1963 Webster family correspondence, 60 items (Box-folder 27:4)
    Harry was in Washington D. C. with his father and Ann was in Rhodesia with the children. She took a job teaching geography at the local school. Vollie Sanderson and Bill Webster were married.
  - 1964 Webster family correspondence, 60 items (Box-folder 27:5)
    William Webster wrote about the Wolff's and an event at the White House with President Lyndon B. Johnson. (April 17, 1964) He also mentioned that he was presented with the outstanding engineer in New England award. He wrote that he attended Yankee and Rand meetings, and raved about a conference at Sterling Forest. He mentioned that he was ready to retire. He wrote that he appointed Fitz Leigh to succeed Harry Hanson. William (Barney) was accepted into Groton.
  - 1965 Webster family correspondence, 19 items (Box-folder 27:6)
    Ann wrote to Harry while he was in [Santo Domingo] about being careful there. She mentioned that she was looking for a glimpse of him on the news every day. She did not want the children to know his location since they could see how dangerous it was there.
  - 1966 Webster family correspondence, 53 items (Box-folder 27:7)
    William Webster continued writing about his many meetings with New England Electric System, Hyuck, MItre, Atomic Energy Commission and efforts by many people to create one atomic power plant. Harry mentioned talking with Robert Ellsworth. William and Vollie Webster travelled to Europe and the Caribbean.
  - 1967 January-September Webster family correspondence, 37 items (Box-folder 27:8)
    Ann and Harry and children were living in Holland. William and Vollie Webster travelled to the west coast and Hawaii. William Webster wrote notes about various colleagues as candidates for high positions in power companies. He was preparing to transfer his leadership role in NEES and EEI so he could retire. There are letters about his Atomic energy citation.
  - 1967 October-December Webster family correspondence, 38 items (Box-folder 28:1)
    William wrote about his busy schedule and various trips and meetings. There are also letters from William (Barney) at Groton, and Liza.
  - 1968 January-May Webster family correspondence, 50 items (Box-folder 28:2)
    William wrote about his trip out west and that Steve Webster was not well. He also mentioned career plans of some of his colleagues. William referred to their "Brazil Deal." Topics mentioned but not detailed, were that labor negations were slow and that Cool Branch Farm had lost a lot of money; the power company lost their gas case with the Supreme Court; gold crisis; atomic desalting plant with the Israeli's; and the death of Martin Luther King. He also made a comment about civil rights saying that "the country has a pretty tough road to walk…" William advised Harry to keep in touch with Robert Ellsworth because he was an important contact in government.
  - 1968 June-September Webster family correspondence, 46 items (Box-folder 28:3)
    William Webster wrote about his visit to Ann and Harry in Holland; and news about AETNA, Hyuck, New England Electric System, and other meetings and stocks.
  - 1968 October-December Webster family correspondence, 33 items (Box-folder 28:4)
    William wrote about United States Security and Exchange Commission hearings, Atomic Energy Commission's General Advisory Committee and other meetings including an invitation by Lewis Strauss to join scientists working for President Nixon. William wrote that the scientists were referred to as the "dinosaur wing" of the scientific community. Harry wrote about conflicts with his boss, X and studied alternative courses of career options with William. His boss was trying to force him into an assignment in Saigon. Harry and William were meeting with Robert Ellsworth to obtain a position for Harry as a liaison to Ellsworth.
  - 1969 January-March Webster family correspondence, 35 items (Box-folder 28:5)
    Harry was travelling to Madrid, Spain. Harry was still writing to William about his career. Ellsworth had just been appointed secretary to President Richard M. Nixon. Harry was considering leaving his current position in July.
  - 1969 April-May Webster family correspondence, 35 items (Box-folder 28:6)
    Harry was working in Madrid, Spain and [Granada] There is a newspaper clipping about Robert Ellsworth being appointed to the position of Ambassador of NATO (North Atlantic Treaty Organization), and suggests that Ellsworth was becoming out of favor with the administration. William wrote that [Richard] Helms agreed that Robert Ellison could use a liaison man (Harry). According to William, Ellsworth felt President Nixon would support his efforts to hire Harry. William was attending and testifying in SEC hearings. There is also information about stocks including the Rock of Ages.
  - 1969 June-July Webster family correspondence, 24 items (Box-folder 29:1)
    William wrote about the Security and Exchange Commission hearings, Atomic Energy Commission's General Advisory Committee and Hyuck meetings. Circumstances made it difficult for Ellsworth to follow through on the liaison position. Harry and Ann prepared for their move back to the United States.
  - 1969 August-December Webster family correspondence, 43 items (Box-folder 29:2)
    Harry asked for a six month leave without pay and resigned. Cornelia Gordon died of a pill overdose during the night of September 21 st. William and Vollie travelled to Athens, Rome and Paris for a Hyuck meetings and Florida for [Association of Illinois Electric Cooperatives] and [Edison Electric Institute] conferences. Soon after Harry retired, his boss was [fired] and the door was opened for Harry to return. William and Harry often mentioned a man high up in the government that they referred to as "Pooh." He seemed to work closely with William and was two levels above Harry's boss. There is a letter from Harry to William that indicated that "Pooh" was "livid" at the way "X" treated Harry. Harry also wrote that Princeton turned coed and he was not in favor of it.
  - 1970 January-April Webster family correspondence, 52 items (Box-folder 29:3)
    Harry travelled through the southern United States and met with ministers and news paper editors including Rev. John Spong (brother of the Senator), Staige Blackford, Jr., Oliver Jones, and Overton Jones about possible jobs and contacts. Harry wrote that he met with [Donald] Rumsfeld and [Frank C.] Carlucci (who became Deputy Director of the CIA in 1978) and ran the Office of Economic Opportunity, William Tyler, (Ambassador of the Hague) Peter Flannigan, Dick Loeb, and Roemer McPhee. William wrote accepting a short term job as senior technical advisor to the AEC (Atomic Energy Commission) and IAEC (International Atomic Energy Agency) for the United Nations International Conference in Geneva on peaceful uses of atomic energy while maintaining his positions with NEPOL, MIT, Hyuck, EEI, NEES, Rand and others. William also mentioned a meeting with the United Nations Scientific Advisory Committee. He also described labor strikes and negotiations with [Spraque. ]Enclosed is a copy of a speech William gave at MIT.
  - 1970 May-September Webster family correspondence, 36 items (Box-folder 29:4)
    Harry wrote William about contacts and leads, including Henry Loomis, Bob Krause, Roger Jones, Arthur Arundel, (newspaper owner and head of Piedmont Environmental Council), Lewis Strauss, George McGhee, and Julian Stein. He was working part time with [the Essex Institute] in Alexandria regarding issues in Puerto Rico. He decided to return to his previous job but in new area called "U. S. Army Personnel Research and Assessment Group," to be referred to a Department of Defense by family and friends. There is a note from William T. Golden. William Webster wrote that he was asked to host Neil Armstrong. Included is a letter from Liza Webster describing protests against the Vietnam War. William Webster started undergoing dialysis.
  - 1970 October-December Webster family correspondence, 22 items (Box-folder 29:5)
    Harry wrote about an easy return to work and fifty percent of his time to be spent in New York working for [Rod Rodgriquez].
  - 1971 Webster family correspondence, 23 items (Box-folder 29:6)
    William wrote that he was reappointed to the Board of NEES and chairman of Yankee but had given up everything else. William Webster III graduated from Princeton; Harry was working in West Germany.
  - 1972 Webster family correspondence, 31 items (Box-folder 29:7)
    Harry was working in Indonesia; and Lusaka, Zambia. Death of William Webster; and Life insurance information from William Webster's estate.
  - 1972 Webster family correspondence: Letters of sympathy after the death of William Webster, 45 items (Box-folder 29:8)
    Letters of sympathy from friends of Harry and William Webster include Robert Ellsworth, Peter Mansfield, Irwin L. Moore, Andrew Onderdonk, Roger Coe, Don Allen, Caroline Conant, and many others.
  - 1973 Webster family correspondence, 32 items (Box-folder 30:1)
    Harry was planning his retirement. Ann wrote to Harry about Watergate and commented on how the Nixon administration worked.
  - 1974 Webster family correspondence, 42 items (Box-folder 30:2)
    There is mostly family correspondence with Ann, Harry, their children, Steve Webster and Vollie Webster.
  - 1975 January-May Webster family correspondence, 52 items (Box-folder 30:3)
    Harry wrote to Vollie that there had been a lot of information about his old outfit in the news and he was glad that he got out when he did.
  - 1975 June-December Webster family correspondence, 32 items (Box-folder 30:4)
  - 1976 Webster family correspondence, 26 items (Box-folder 30:5)
    Harry travelled to San Jose, Costa Rico; Guatamala; and Columbia. He had been planning to work with Hubert Humphrey, Joe Crangle and Paul Simon's campaign but it fell through. He was also involved in fund raising for Daniel Patrick Moynihan for the Senate Committee and wanted a permanent job working for him. He also mentioned sitting next to Barry Goldwater and described him as a "warm guy."
  - 1977 Webster family correspondence, 47 items (Box-folder 30:6)
    Harry went to San Jose ("his favorite small country") and Columbia for presidential primaries.
  - 1978 Webster family correspondence, 50 items (Box-folder 30:7)
    Harry travelled to Mexico, San Jose, Ecuador, and other places in Central America. Harry wrote that he attended a small political gathering at Sargent Shriver's place and was not impressed with Shriver.
  - 1979 Webster family correspondence, 25 items (Box-folder 30:8)
    Ann and Harry travelled to Canada. Harry wrote to Vollie that he had been talking to several "Bush men" and might start working for them part time.
  - 1980 Webster family correspondence, 18 items (Box-folder 31:1)
    Ann and Harry travelled to Mexico. Harry visited San Jose, and sent Vollie news clippings about the Reagan/Bush victory. Harry wrote to Vollie that they were invited to the inauguration and parties.
  - 1981 Webster family correspondence, 21 items (Box-folder 31:2)
  - 1982 Webster family correspondence, 48 items (Box-folder 31:3)
    Harry visited San Jose and Honduras. Ann and Harry travelled to England, France, Greece, Turkey, and Israel. Ann and Harry also went out west to visit their children. Ann finished undergraduate and graduate courses in Anthropology and became an Anthropology teacher at George Washington University.
  - 1983 January-June Webster family correspondence, 39 items (Box-folder 31:4)
    Harry went to San Jose and Ann travelled to England and France.
  - 1983 July-December Webster family correspondence, 42 items (Box-folder 31:5)
    There is a letter to Harry from Rod Rodgriquez (who was his boss and friend in the CIA). Rodriquez mentioned that the thought of Kissinger coming back made him "… sick at my stomach" There is a letter from [Clyde] who was a close colleague of Harry's and the George H. W. Bush family.
  - 1984 January-June Webster family correspondence, 25 items (Box-folder 31:6)
    Letters reveal that Harry was visiting their daughters out west, and in Mexico. There are also letters from Steve Webster and to the family, including Vollie Webster.
  - 1984 July-December Webster family correspondence, 38 items (Box-folder 31:7)
    There are photographs of Ann and Harry's first grandchild, Sarah Nemiah Ladd (daughter of Liza and John Ladd).
  - 1985 Webster family correspondence, 58 items (Box-folder 31:8)
    Harry, Ann, and their daughter Maggie travelled to Mexico, Buenos Aires, Rio de Janeiro, and Bogota.
  - 1986 Webster family correspondence, 45 items (Box-folder 32:1)
    Harry was in Ireland; Weld, Maine; and Canada.
  - 1987 January-June Webster family correspondence, 32 items (Box-folder 32:2)
    Harry visited San Francisco and Europe with his son Armistead Churchill Gordon ("Oppit"). There is a description of Harry's grandfather, Judge Edward "Peter" Willard Blodgett (-1949) written by Harry.
  - 1987 July-December 1986 Webster family correspondence, 38 items (Box-folder 32:3)
    Harry was on his annual trip to Weld. Ann was in Europe and Nairobi. Harry wrote two accounts of his trips abroad and Holland. Ann was recovering from an illness from her trip abroad. Harry mentioned Paul Simon's presidential campaign.
  - 1988 Webster family correspondence, 14 items (Box-folder 32:4)
    Harry travelled to Costa Rica, Holland, Germany, Austria, Hungary, Rumania, and Istanbul with his daughter, Liza.
  - 1989 Webster family correspondence, 48 items (Box-folder 32:5)
    Ann and Harry continued to travel to their favorite places around the world.
  - 1990 Webster family correspondence, 26 items (Box-folder 32:6)
    Death of Steve Webster
  - 1991 Webster family correspondence, 37 items (Box-folder 32:7)
  - 1992 Webster family correspondence, 15 items (Box-folder 33:1)
  - 1993 Webster family correspondence, 22 items (Box-folder 33:2)
  - 1994 Webster family correspondence, 31 items (Box-folder 33:3)
    Ann Gordon Webster died in November.
  - 1995 Webster family correspondence, 17 items (Box-folder 33:4)
  - 1996-1997 Webster family correspondence, 9 items (Box-folder 33:5)
  - n. d. Webster family correspondence, 52 items (Box-folder 33:6)
  - n. d. Address List, 5 items (Box-folder 33:7)
  - 19361947-1950 Webster general correspondence, 32 items (Box-folder 33:8)
    Letters to Ann and or Harry include correspondents, Percy Redmund, Abbot Fletcher, Donald J. Sterling, Peter S. Mansfield, Mary Nold, Anne Hale, Don Manders, Thirsa Proctor, and James Page Elder.
  - 1951-1952 Webster general correspondence, 32 items (Box-folder 34:1)
    Correspondents include Abbot Fletcher, Mrs. Thomas J. Rigney, Jr., Mrs. Richard C. Gillett, Mrs. Mathew Pratt, Corporal F. J.L. Brokaw, Mary Pierce, Mr. and Mrs. Kindred, Martha "Martee" Chanutin, Peter S. Mansfield, Margaret Macleod, and Robert M. Dinsmore.
  - 1953-1954 Webster general correspondence, 24 items (Box-folder 34:2)
    Correspondents include Sallie Starker, Gertrude Fitzhugh, GiGi McKnight, Margaret Macleod, Donald J. Sterling, Frances Malther, and Mrs. (Julia) James Southall Wilson.
  - 1955 Webster general correspondence, 33 items (Box-folder 34:3)
    Correspondents include Eileen Fletcher, Charlotte W. Gibbons, Frances Walther, Maria M. Morgan, Brigadier General Harry A. Barber, Jr., Frank and Jeannette Geldard, Edward Peck Curtis, Jr., Charles M. Bounds, Jr., and Robert Owen.
  - 1956 Webster general correspondence, 6 items (Box-folder 34:4)
    Correspondents include Frances Walther, Thirsa Proctor, Sallie Starker, and Frances Walther.
  - 1957 Webster general correspondence, 20 items (Box-folder 34:5)
    Correspondents include Margaret Hench Underwood, Robert and Vivian Owen, Frances Walther, Abbot Fletcher, Mrs. Catherine Perkins, Don Larrimore, Norman and Jean Reddaway, and David Archie.
  - 1958-1959 Webster general correspondence, 14 items (Box-folder 34:6)
    Correspondents include Charlotte Gibbons, Helen Kelly, Sally and John Baker, Maurice Wilson, Mrs. Mathew Pratt, Bill Gorman, Mrs. Peregrine Spencer Churchill, and Steve Close.
  - 1960 Webster general correspondence, 20 items (Box-folder 34:7)
    Mrs. Peregrine Spencer Churchill, James Page Elder, Allen E. Henkin, John Caswell, D. C. Stevens, Jeanne Robinson, Mary Bucknall, Joseph and Mary Crowley, Joan and Andrew Phelan, Mrs. A. E. Davidson, Jane C. Johnson, and Peter S. Mansfield.
  - 1961 Webster general correspondence, 43 items (Box-folder 34:8)